Thomas Rohée

Email: roheethomas@gmail.com

About

Interested in computers in general, I enjoy programming, building and using them in different forms. While machine learning can be applied in multiple ways, I'm interested in using it as a tool to optimize automated processes or tedious manual tasks that couldn't be easily automated before. This involves understanding processes and learning from domain experts in order to successfully deploy a useful model or machine learning pipeline.

Experience

Al Developer at Logibec

October 2017 – Today

- Responsible for the development of a machine learning pipeline supporting a new application predicting the risk of patients' readmission before being discharged from the hospital. The application technology stack involved Apache Spark with Scala, Postgresql, Python, Flask, and Scikit-learn.
- Involved in grant applications and coordination between Logibec, clients and academic researchers in order to get federal and provincial public funding for new machine learning projects relevant for healthcare organisations.
- Supervision of machine learning interns from Mila who were responsible for analysing data and developing new models relevant for the clients.
- Involved in producing internal training material on fundamentals of AI.

Machine learning specialist at Datacratic/iPerceptions Juin 2015 – September 2017

- Responsible for online real-time bidding advertising campaign performance made through Datacratic RTB-Opt product. Making sure campaign managers get the best ROI possible by monitoring machine learning models performance on key metrics (Click-Through Rate, Cost Per Click, Cost Per Acquisition).
- Continuously improving the campaign optimization in order to fill campaign managers needs: enable optimization on small campaigns. Improve the system C++ and Python technology stack in order to support new use cases and improve every day operations.
- Development of a machine learning pipeline in Golang using Amazon AWS machine learning and Kubernetes to drive the new audience recognition technology.

Machine learning Intern at Datacratic

September 2014 - January 2015

- Research and development on application of neural networks for online real-time bidding advertising problems. Namely, predict accurately the probability of click by the user given an ad impression.

Research assistant at Mila, University of Montreal

September 2013 – September 2014

- Help develop a Python tool to ease comparisons between machine learning models and enable research for new models for the facial landmarks recognition task.
- Contributions to Pylearn2, a Mila library to ease machine learning model training workflow, in the form of refactoring the codebase and improving logging.

Education

Online courses

- Functional Programming Principles in Scala (Coursera)

- Principles of Reactive Programming (Coursera)
- Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree Program (Udacity)

Université de Montréal – Master of computer science 2013- 2015

Courses:

- Foundation of machine learning
- Machine learning algorithms
- Quantum information science
- Semantic of programming languages

SUPINFO International University – Bachelor of Science with Honours 2009 - 2013

Computer Science and Information System.